{
  "theme": [
    {
      "Questions": [
        {
          "Question": "Who painted the famous artwork 'Mona Lisa'?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Leonardo da Vinci",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Pablo Picasso",
            "Vincent van Gogh",
            "Claude Monet"
          ],
          "Explanation": "Leonardo da Vinci is the artist behind the iconic painting 'Mona Lisa', created during the Renaissance period."
        },
        {
          "Question": "Which artist is known for his 'Campbell's Soup Cans' artwork?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Andy Warhol",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Salvador Dali",
            "Jackson Pollock",
            "Piet Mondrian"
          ],
          "Explanation": "Andy Warhol, a leading figure in the pop art movement, is famous for his 'Campbell's Soup Cans' artwork."
        },
        {
          "Question": "Who sculpted the masterpiece 'David'?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Michelangelo",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Auguste Rodin",
            "Pablo Picasso",
            "Donatello"
          ],
          "Explanation": "Michelangelo, an Italian artist, created the renowned sculpture 'David' during the Renaissance period."
        },
        {
          "Question": "Which artist is associated with the painting 'Starry Night'?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Vincent van Gogh",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Leonardo da Vinci",
            "Pablo Picasso",
            "Claude Monet"
          ],
          "Explanation": "Vincent van Gogh is the artist behind the famous painting 'Starry Night', known for its swirling sky."
        },
        {
          "Question": "Who is the creator of the 'Sistine Chapel Ceiling' frescoes?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Michelangelo",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Leonardo da Vinci",
            "Raphael",
            "Caravaggio"
          ],
          "Explanation": "Michelangelo painted the breathtaking frescoes on the ceiling of the Sistine Chapel in Vatican City."
        },
        {
          "Question": "Which artist is known for his 'Water Lilies' series?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Claude Monet",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Salvador Dali",
            "Pablo Picasso",
            "Vincent van Gogh"
          ],
          "Explanation": "Claude Monet, a French impressionist, is famous for his series of paintings called 'Water Lilies'."
        },
        {
          "Question": "Who painted the iconic artwork 'The Persistence of Memory'?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Salvador Dali",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Edvard Munch",
            "Gustav Klimt",
            "Frida Kahlo"
          ],
          "Explanation": "Salvador Dali is the artist behind the surreal painting 'The Persistence of Memory', featuring melting clocks."
        },
        {
          "Question": "Which artist is known for his 'Guernica' painting?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Pablo Picasso",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Leonardo da Vinci",
            "Vincent van Gogh",
            "Claude Monet"
          ],
          "Explanation": "Pablo Picasso, a Spanish artist, created the powerful anti-war painting 'Guernica'."
        },
        {
          "Question": "Who is the artist behind the 'Marilyn Monroe' silkscreen prints?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Andy Warhol",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Jackson Pollock",
            "Salvador Dali",
            "Piet Mondrian"
          ],
          "Explanation": "Andy Warhol popularized the 'Marilyn Monroe' silkscreen prints, showcasing his fascination with celebrity culture."
        },
        {
          "Question": "Which artist is known for his 'The Birth of Venus' painting?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Sandro Botticelli",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Rembrandt",
            "Hieronymus Bosch",
            "Titian"
          ],
          "Explanation": "Sandro Botticelli, an Italian painter, created the iconic painting 'The Birth of Venus' during the Renaissance period."
        },
        {
          "Question": "Who is the artist behind the 'The Starry Night' painting?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Vincent van Gogh",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Leonardo da Vinci",
            "Pablo Picasso",
            "Claude Monet"
          ],
          "Explanation": "Vincent van Gogh painted the mesmerizing artwork 'The Starry Night', depicting a dreamy night sky."
        },
        {
          "Question": "Which artist is known for his 'The Last Supper' mural?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Leonardo da Vinci",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Michelangelo",
            "Raphael",
            "Caravaggio"
          ],
          "Explanation": "Leonardo da Vinci painted the famous mural 'The Last Supper', portraying the biblical event."
        },
        {
          "Question": "Who is the creator of the 'The Thinker' sculpture?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Auguste Rodin",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Michelangelo",
            "Pablo Picasso",
            "Donatello"
          ],
          "Explanation": "Auguste Rodin, a French sculptor, crafted the renowned sculpture 'The Thinker'."
        },
        {
          "Question": "Which artist is associated with the painting 'Girl with a Pearl Earring'?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Johannes Vermeer",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Edvard Munch",
            "Gustav Klimt",
            "Frida Kahlo"
          ],
          "Explanation": "Johannes Vermeer is the artist behind the captivating painting 'Girl with a Pearl Earring'."
        },
        {
          "Question": "Who painted the masterpiece 'The Creation of Adam' on the Sistine Chapel ceiling?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Michelangelo",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Leonardo da Vinci",
            "Raphael",
            "Caravaggio"
          ],
          "Explanation": "Michelangelo painted the iconic 'The Creation of Adam' on the Sistine Chapel ceiling."
        },
        {
          "Question": "Which artist is known for his 'Les Demoiselles d'Avignon' painting?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Pablo Picasso",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Salvador Dali",
            "Vincent van Gogh",
            "Claude Monet"
          ],
          "Explanation": "Pablo Picasso created the groundbreaking painting 'Les Demoiselles d'Avignon', marking the beginning of Cubism."
        },
        {
          "Question": "Who is the artist behind the 'The Birth of Venus' painting?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Sandro Botticelli",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Rembrandt",
            "Hieronymus Bosch",
            "Titian"
          ],
          "Explanation": "Sandro Botticelli painted the famous artwork 'The Birth of Venus', depicting the goddess of love."
        },
        {
          "Question": "Which artist is known for his 'The Persistence of Memory' painting?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Salvador Dali",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Edvard Munch",
            "Gustav Klimt",
            "Frida Kahlo"
          ],
          "Explanation": "Salvador Dali is the artist behind the surreal painting 'The Persistence of Memory', featuring melting clocks."
        },
        {
          "Question": "Who is the creator of the 'The Thinker' sculpture?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Auguste Rodin",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Michelangelo",
            "Pablo Picasso",
            "Donatello"
          ],
          "Explanation": "Auguste Rodin, a French sculptor, crafted the renowned sculpture 'The Thinker'."
        },
        {
          "Question": "Which artist is associated with the painting 'The Starry Night'?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Vincent van Gogh",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Leonardo da Vinci",
            "Pablo Picasso",
            "Claude Monet"
          ],
          "Explanation": "Vincent van Gogh is the artist behind the famous painting 'The Starry Night', known for its swirling sky."
        }
      ]
    }
  ]
}